Entry-Level Data Analytics Professional

Recently Graduated in Applied Mathematics with internship experience in Python programming and university courses involving the implementation of models to interpret data including techniques in Machine Learning. I continue to advance my skills with tools such as Tableau and MySQL through online courses. Business development and operations oriented.

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis | Bachelor of Science in Applied Mathematics

December 2022

Relevant coursework:

- <u>Mathematics of Data Analytics</u> Ranking algorithms, classification, and optimization.
- Machine Learning Polynomial Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, PCA, SVM-classification, K-means clustering, and Neural Networks in Python from scratch.

SKILLS

Programming languages: Python, SQL fundamentals, C++, MATLAB

Operating systems: Windows, Linux

Software tools: Excel, Tableau, GitHub, PowerPoint, LaTeX

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intern - Cell2Fire | Davis, CA

6/2021 - 5/2022

- Identified a key issue in the output of a forest fire propagation simulator and solved the problem by writing an appropriate Python script, including debugging a Fortran program in the process to ensure all variables were factored in the predictions.
- Created detailed instructions with images to access visualization tools using Sphinx to generate directions in an html web format document.

Researcher - Hack for California | Davis, CA

9/2020 - 12/2020

- Arranged team meetings with the UC Davis Center for Regional Change to launch project for displacement data analysis in Central Valley communities attaining approval for project proposal.
- Accessed census data with API key to obtain demographics in census tracts within San Joaquin County.

Biomedical Research Intern - SFSU Bridges to Baccalaureate | San Francisco, CA

5/2018 - 8/2018

- Presented research findings at a poster symposium event with hundreds of attendees including university research professors and students.
- Research included testing the effects of gene protein tags in cell signaling for potential cancer treatment
 insights as well as experiments to test claims of ingestible SPF products. Excel was used to collect data
 for these experiments and illustrate results with graphs.

LEADERSHIP

Mathematics Tutoring | Oakland, CA

3/2020 - 8/2020

- Developed lessons and tutored 2 children and 2 adults in mathematics as an independent tutor.
- Instructed for preparation in GED and GRE testing in-person and remotely.

Toastmasters | San Francisco, CA

8/2018 - 1/2019

 Conducted speeches to a group of 12-15 members and visitors, evaluated speeches, and organized and lead a 1.5 hr. meeting as a member of Spanish Bilingual SF Toastmasters club, receiving positive feedback from experienced professionals.